Sam Protsenko

Software Engineer

Ukraine, Kyiv ☐ +38 097 5277313 ☑ joe.skb7@gmail.com ☐ joe-skb7



Summary

Embedded software engineer with more than 10 years of professional experience. Main area of expertise is Linux kernel, bootloaders, firmwares and system level user space programming on ARM-based devices. For the last 5 years has been contributing to open-source projects and been involved with upstreaming activity. Has prior background in cross-platform applications development, algorithms and electronics. Active member of open-source community, mentor, speaker.

Experience

2020- Software Engineer, Linaro

Present Linaro Consumer Group Kernel Team

2018–2020 Team Lead, GlobalLogic, Kyiv

Project: Texas Instruments (Linaro assignee for LCG).

Role: Supporting the BeagleBoard X15 board and upstreaming work.

- O Porting Android to a new board and upstreaming it with a small team: [1]
- O Adopting VPN from upstream kernel in AOSP: [2]
- O Implementing Android 10 boot sequence: [3]
- O Running Android 10 with mainline kernel on BeagleBoard X15

2012–2018 Software Engineer, GlobalLogic, Kyiv

Projects: Texas Instruments (directly and as Linaro assignee for LEG and LMG), others. Role: Platform development in Linux kernel and bootloaders, upstreaming.

- Implementing and supporting device drivers: [4]
- Maintaining boot sequence and fastboot in U-Boot: [5]
- Board bring ups
- O Bug fixing (drivers, device tree, bootloader)
- Migrating to new kernel versions
- O Implementing XIP boot from NOR flash (automotive)
- O System boot time optimizations (automotive)
- Supporting Android kernel on TI OMAP4/OMAP5 SoC

2009–2012 **Software Developer**, AlterEGO, Kramatorsk

Role: Cross-platform software design and coding (C++/Qt).

Education

2004–2009 **Specialist degree**, Donbas State Mechanical Engineering Academy, Kramatorsk Speciality: Automation of technological processes

Computer skills

Languages C, C++, Bash Projects Linux kernel, U-Boot, Android

CPUs ARM32, AArch64, x86 MCUs AM57x, AM65x, STM32, MSP430

Tools GCC, GDB, Make, Git, Vim Hardware JTAG, scope, logical analyzer

Languages

Ukrainian Fluent

English Upper-intermediate Speaking, reading and writing

Other Activities

2011–Today Maintainer of "INSTEAD" Debian package: [6]

2015–Today Active member on StackOverflow (>10k reputation): [7]

2019 Organizer of "Root Linux Conference" in Kyiv: [8]

2018–Today Creator and instructor of Linux kernel course: [9]

2017–2019 Speaker at Linaro and GlobalLogic events

References

- [1] https://android-review.googlesource.com/q/author:protsenko
- [2] https://connect.linaro.org/resources/bkk19/bkk19-414/
- [3] https://connect.linaro.org/resources/san19/san19-217/
- [4] https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git/log/?qt=author&q=protsenko
- [5] https://gitlab.denx.de/u-boot/u-boot/-/commits/master?search=protsenko
- [6] http://packages.debian.org/sid/instead
- [7] https://stackoverflow.com/users/3866447/sam-protsenko
- [8] https://linux.globallogic.com/
- [9] https://github.com/joe-skb7/kernel-lectures

My native language